伊朗革命引发石油危机
经济陷入一片混乱
能够掌握能源
就能控制全世界
因此许多暗杀计划蠢蠢欲动
小子，你搞什么？
HUNTER: Hey, kiddo, what are you doing?
拿我买的美味墨西哥餐喂狗
I buy you a fancy Mexican meal and you're feeding it to a mutt.
哪里美味！
Real fancy.
你知道那是什么吗？
You have any idea what that is?
什么？
What?
树鸡
Tree chicken.
- 那是什么？ - 墨西哥圣品
What? That's what the locals call it.
能治感冒宿醉
Colds, headaches, hangovers, cures anything.
还可治百病，据说成份是蜥蜴
Iguana. That's what they say.
那消化不良呢？
What about indigestion?
就吃蜥蜴饼
Fuckin' iguana taco.
你在萨尔瓦多吃过了
Yeah, well, you had it in Salvador.
对，难吃死了
Yeah, and that was shit.
安哥拉呢？那里的菜好吃吧？
What about Angola? The food was good there, right?
难吃
Shit.
那罗德西亚呢？
Yeah, Rhodesia?
难吃
Shit.
- 汉堡呢？ - 也难吃
Hamburg? Shit.
所以只要离开纽约
So if it's not New York, it's...
东西就变难吃
You got it. Shit.
你真是暴殄天物
Look at you wasting away.
我们该回纽约混饭吃
We got to get a job in New York.
这很简单，那里多半是废物
That won't be a problem. Plenty of assholes there.
该走了，小子
Time to move, kiddo.
墨西哥，乔伊达市
好啦、好啦
MEIER: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
靠！
Fuck!
趴下！
Stay down!
找掩护，小子！
HUNTER: Stay down, kid.
为何愣住！
What happened?
- 车里有小孩 - 什么？
There was a kid in the car.What?
车里有小孩！
There was a kid in the car.
快、快、快
Go, go, go, go!
靠！
Fuck!
受够了，我要退出
I'm done with this. I'm finished.
没办法
I can't do this anymore.
我下不了手
I can't do this.
特种精英
真实故事，剽悍改编
一年后，澳洲  亚拉河谷
该死！
Oh, shit!
Shit!
两天后，阿拉伯- 阿曼
丹尼上车
AGENT: Danny, get in.
这里的人一堆怪病  我不想下车
These camel jockeys have got diseases I don't wanna think about.
他人呢？
Where is he?
还在客户手上
The client still has him.
什么客户？
What client?
我们现在就过去
We're going there now.
快点走吧！
Okay, drive.
客户是一位石油酋长
AGENT: So the client's an oil sheikh, no less.
过去曾掌管一大片沙漠
He used to rule some huge stretch of desert till his tribe kicked him out.
之后就搬到这里
Been living here in exile ever since.
总之，酋长花钱要找人办事
Anyway, Sheikhy was loaded and he wanted a job done.
杭特拿了钱，人却落跑
Hunter took the contract, then he ran.
他们在机场逮到他
They caught him at the airport.
然后呢？
And?
如你所见，全写在信里
You know the rest. You got the package.
我看到了，什么任务？
Yeah, I got it.
只知道价钱，杭特没提太多细节
What's the job? Just came with a price tag, no details. Hunter took it cold.
为何不说？
Why would he do that?
付了六百万美金，是个大数目
Six million dollars. A big score, Danny.
对杭特来说太多了
Too bloody big for Hunter.
是啊，他不值这么多
Yeah. Why'd you offer it to him?
他需要钱，你则想退出，记得吗？
He wanted the money. And you were out, remember?
现在还是
Yeah. Still am.
我拒绝拿枪
I'm done with killing.
这可由不得你
Yeah, well, maybe killing ain't done with you.
杭特需要你，那个带种的铁汉丹尼
Hunter needs the old Danny, the best in the biz.
如此响当当的称号！
The one with balls of steel. You remember him, right?
奉劝你，尽早回到现实…
Look, it comes down to this.
你不出手，杭特就死定了
You don't do this job, Hunter's a dead man.
他们正在等你
They're waiting for you.
往这边
This way.
他只是在等眼睛适应
SHEIKH AMR: He's waiting for his eyes to adjust.
小心留意
Be careful around this one, boy.
我儿子离开沙漠太久
My son forgets the ways of the desert.
战争后
Since our war against the Sultan, all he has had of his homeland
他已无法嗅出野狠的味道
is this paint. Plaster.
我大儿子胡笙就在这里遇害
My first son, Hussain, was slaughtered here.
死在他儿子面前
Shot before his children.
还有这里，那场米尔白战役
And here, at the Battle of Mirbat,
二儿子萨林负伤后身亡
his brother, Salim, was wounded and then killed. Murdered.
后来我第三个儿子阿里
And then my third son was taken from me. Ali.
也被追杀致死
Hunted down and slaughtered.
沙漠中有定律，灵魂要得到救赎
The law of the desert says the blood of the victim
必须杀了凶手的血来祭拜
must be washed away by the blood of the Killers.
但我隐忍报复
But I refused revenge
带着小儿子巴海逃避战火
and saved my last son, Bakhait, from the war.
因此被部落逐出沙漠
So I was exiled to this desert.
我再有财有势
I have wealth, power.
也终将一死
But rich men die, too.
等我死后
When I die,
我希望巴海能回到部落
I want Bakhait to go home to my tribe.
不过在这之前
But for that to happen,
杀死我儿子们的凶手得先死
the killers of my sons must be killed.
这不需要我们动手
You don't need me or Hunter for this.
你有足够人手
You got all the men you need.
我的人无法入境英国！
What use would my men be in England?
英国？
England?
英国人派出精锐部队
The English sent their fiercest
展开石油杀戮战
dogs to kill for the Sultan's oil.
航空特种军团？
The SAS?
对，他们是最具侵略性的战士
Yes. Their glorious special forces.
你儿子光荣战死
那不是战争，是掠夺
It was a war. It was not England's war.
他们入侵阿拉伯，谋杀我儿子
They came to my land, murdered my sons,
现在他们要接受制裁
now they will face my law.
医生说我只剩六个月可活
The doctors say I have six months left to live.
你要在我死之前完成报仇
You must avenge my sons before I die
不然你朋友就会跟我一起死
or your friend will die with me.
我不在乎你怎么杀他们
I don't care how you kill the Killers.
但他们要在镜头前承认罪行
But they will admit their guilt on tape,
他们的死要像意外
and their deaths must look like accidents.
完全与巴海无关
This must not lead back to my son.
去吧！让英国佬明白
So go, show the English
战争必须双方同意才能终止
a war isn't over till both sides say it is.
我要见杭特
I wanna see Hunter.
丹尼，不…
Oh, Danny! No, Danny. No, no, no, no. No.
你在这里干嘛？快走
What are you doing here? Get out of here.
你没事吧？
You all right?
我没事？很好
Am I all right? Yeah, I'm all right.
你快走，离开这里，快
You gotta go. Get away from here. Go, go, go, go.
我不是为你来的，是替你家人而来
I'm not here for you anyway. I was thinking about the girls and Celine.
我想也是
Me, too. Me, too.
这话什么意思？
(CHUCKLES) What's that supposed to mean?
养家活口很难的
It's tough putting food on the table.
你怎么说？六百万连问都不问？
What you feeding 'em? Six million, no questions?
这个嘛
Well.
你早知道，那肯定是鸟差事
So you must've known that was a bullshit job.
我只知道，特勤队是一条不归路
Yeah, I knew. Fuckin' SAS, a one-way ticket for sure.
你接了差事，我不能把你扔在这
Well, you took the job, and I'm not leaving you here.
拿点酒来！
Give this man a drink.
我很想你
I missed you.
别想我！
I didn't miss you.
退出这行是对的
Every day you were out of this game was a good day for me.
我以你为荣
I was proud of you when you got out.
千万别再进来
Stay out.
太迟了！
Too late.
你该保持距离
You should have stayed away.
不然就跑快点
Or run faster.
混帐东西
Son of a bitch!
- 你干嘛？ - 我拿回我的表
What are you doing? Let me get my watch back.
快！快！
Go, go!
快！快开门
Go, go, get the door!
快开门！
Get the door!
枪给我
Give me the gun.
表现太赞了！
Bravo! Bravo!
若想中枪，我很乐意送你
If you need to be shot, I'll happily oblige.
对不起，小子
I'm sorry, kiddo.
我父亲要留活口
My father needs him alive.
有你的
Nice try.
你知道你逃不了
You know they'd have found you.
总会被找到
Everybody gets found.
你早知道了！
You knew.
你也知道杭特不愿意接任务
My gut tells me you knew the target and you knew Hunter wouldn't take it.
用他当诱饵钧我
You used him as bait.
这是误会！
That's a lot of angles, Danny.
丹尼，你以为我有那能耐？
Do you think I'm that smart?
出去！
Get out.
你也滚出去
And you. Out.
我怀念当年跟你共舞
ANNE: We missed you at the dance last night.
我不大会跳舞
DANNY: I'm not much of a dancer.
太久了，我脑海想不起这个片段
Besides, I'm still trying to find out how much house is under this.
是啊，大忙人
Right, big plans.
是啊，真的忙过头
Yeah, maybe too big.
你忘记我了，对吧？
You don't remember me, do you?
对，好一阵子没见
Yeah, well, it's been a while.
我是安海蕾瑟
I'm Anne Frazer.
安海蕾瑟？！
Anne Frazer?
一头乱糟糟的红发
Anne had red hair full of grass.
对啊！
(LAUGHS) Yeah.
穿着一双怪红鞋
And weird red gumboots.
还画上眼睛，我的天啊！
With eyes on them. (LAUGHS) Oh, my God!
法国- 巴黎
你欠我50英镑
Oi! You owe me 50 quid.
我就说他会回来！
Told you he'd be back, didn't I?
我们很想你
We missed you. Yeah?
是阿！所以我来了！
Here I am.
好啦，要开始了吗？
DAVIES: All right, then, you want some?
很好，完全没退步
Yeah, mate, you still got it. Still got that edge.
这才是真正的杀手！
You're a real killer.
我们谈谈吧！
DANNY: Come on, let's talk. (GROANS)
你离开后没结婚吧？
DAVIES: While you were away, you didn't start a family, did you?
没
No.
所以没人靠你养家活口？
So no one's depending on you?
只有杭特
Only Hunter.
这样最好，因为…
'Cause one,
你的对手是特种部队
you're going after the SAS.
他们是一群疯子，彼此相互照应
They're a paranoid bunch. They always got their back up.
再来，你要了解阿曼局势
Two, you need info on Oman.
没有人敢谈阿曼政局
No one talks about Oman.
许多人去当军事顾问
They went in there as advisors and ended up fighting the fucking war. Real hush-hush,
却打起仗来，成了半佣兵
semi-mercenary stuff.
而且，你需要口供
Three, you need confessions.
他们忍受折磨
They're trained to resist torture
所以不管你说什么做什么
so no matter what you say or do, they'll say nothing.
他们都三缄其口
And four, Danny,
最后叮咛，丹尼
this is the best special forces regiment in the world.
他们是最精英的特种部队 海豹特勤队根本不够看
They make the Navy Seals look like a bunch of cupcakes.
更何况！
And not only that,
你一次想干掉三个怪胎
you're trying to take down three of their geezers
还要搞成像一桩意外
and make it look like an accident.
我只求你给我一点支援
All I'm asking is give it some thought.
花一天或更多，反正我非做不可
Take a day, more if you want. I'm going anyway.
我当然会帮忙，笨丹！
Of course I'm in, you silly bastard.
我们是好伙伴
It's what we do, right?
而且，我跟他们也有帐要清
Anyway, I've got a score to settle with them.
我在巴拉斯参加过他们的测验
Tried out for them when I was in the Paras.
最后还是被刷掉
Did Hereford, the whole fucking lot.
什么？他们没要你？
MEIER: What, and they wouldn't have you?
你想要我拿酒瓶塞你屁眼吗？
(SIGHS) You want this bottle shoved up your arse?
你很气吗？要吃棒棒糖吗？
Are you upset? Would you like a lolly?
我想吃
I'd love a lolly.
要草莓还是操没！?
MEIER: Strawberry or fuck you?
麦尔
Meier.
我要加入
In.
为什么？
Why?
六百万就是理由
Ah, six million reasons.
怎么分帐？
So what's the split?
经纪人抽佣后，你们五五分帐
After the Agent takes his slice, 50-50 between you two.
五五分帐？那你呢？
50-50? How about you?
我是为杭特淌浑水的
I'm in this for Hunter.
真感人啊！
How wonderfully touching.
感动阿！可是蠢毙了
Touching, but fuckin' stupid.
酋长只能认出一名凶手
The Sheikh could only ID one of the killers.
要找出其他两个人的名字
I need you to come up with the names on the other two.
从米尔巴战役那个开始
Start with the one they killed at Mirbat.
当前的目标是史帝芬哈里斯
So the one target we do have is Steven Douglas Harris.
他战后仍待在阿曼
Stayed on in Oman after the war.
后来在苏丹军中开直升机
Ended up flying choppers for the Sultan's armed forces.
太好了，这个简单
Great. A juice junkie.
我和麦尔会去那里搞定他
Me and Meier'll head there to track him down.
开工?！丹尼
Boys? Danny.
麦尔
Meier.
阿曼，首都- 马斯喀特
搞什么，滚开！
MAN: What the fuck!
滚开！
是哈里斯！
MAN: Harris!
哈里斯，你这个混蛋！滚啦！
Harris, you prick! Fuck off!
希望他们爱吃加砂的汉堡
Well, I hope the buggers like sand in their burgers, huh?
白色吉普车往你那去，是哈里斯
White Range Rover coming your way. It's Harris.
你干嘛？
SANDY: What are you doing?
拜托，来一发嘛！
Come on, have a go. No.
我不要
Come on. I'm not.
来打一发嘛，瞄准然后射击
Have a go. Look.
来！很好！
Just aim and shoot. Go! Here we go!
你这个色胚！
Oh, you horny git! Come on.
来嘛！来嘛！
No. Come on. (LAUGHS) Come on.
英国   航空特种军团
女士们，赏条内裤当谢礼吧！
DAVIES: All right, ladies, you can throw your knickers if you want.
无聊，你们这群笨蛋
Go on, you cheeky bugger!
你在阿曼服役？
MAN: You serve in Oman? At Mirbat.
在米尔巴，那段日子真爽
That was a day, wasn't it?
米尔巴之役，是场混战
What about Mirbat? That was a right mess, eh?
是不大好
Wasn't good.
友人战死
I had a mate there.
英国   伦敦
- 快接，快点！ - 好…
DIANE: Spike, get that quick. Yeah, all right, all right.
爱哭─闹！
Bollocks.
你好！
Hello?
史派基，我是巴萨
Spikey, it's Bazza.
电话再那么吵，我就砸了它！
God's sake! I'm unplugging that bloody thing next time, and I mean it.
有个自称特种部队的人
Yeah, I'm onto this bloke here, right.
在搜集米尔巴的消息
He was in the Bear earlier pumping some SAS lads for info on Mirbat.
米尔巴？然后呢？
Mirbat. And?
他自称威尔斯人，不过口音不像
He says he's Welsh. But he don't sound it.
我不知道，也许我太多虑
I don't know. Maybe I'm being a bit paranoid, but...
多虑是好事，小心麻烦找上门
Hey, just 'cause you're being paranoid, doesn't mean to say they're not out to get you.
说吧，你得到什么情报
All right, mate, give me what you've got.
好
Okay.
我会派一个人盯牢他
Put one of my Locals onto him.
阿曼大使馆
SPIKE: The Omani Embassy.
我们的人跟他进到签证处
Our Local followed him into the visa section.
他说是威尔斯人，自称琼斯先生
Says he's Welsh, calls himself Mr. Jones.
之后我们就跟丢他
We lost him after he left.
跟丢？怎么会？
FITZ: Lost him? How come?
他没回去取车，那是赃车
He never came back to his car. Stolen.
总之，他四天后飞去阿曼
Anyhow, he flies to Oman in four days.
我想派人去那里盯他
I'd like permission to send one of my boys out there to tail him.
详细调查来历
This was definitely some kind of recce.
那场仗很乱，我们的行动有待商确
That was a dirty war. What we did there was questionable.
阿曼被捣的像蜂窝
Oman is a bloody hornet's nest.
是啊，如果这家伙想下手
Right. And if this bugger is poking at it,
我要知道他是谁
I want to know who he is. I say we send a Local.
我们派人跟，有人反对吗？
Any objections?
注意
Noted.
我们让你挑选人手
We'll leave you to choose the right man.
提醒一下，我们是前特种队员
I'd also like it noted that we are ex-SAS.
我们要保护的人也是
The men we protect are ex-SAS.
而你史派基
And you, Spike,
虽然你不爽还是要承认
though you hate to admit it, are ex-SAS.
记住，我们现在是商人兼银行家
JUSTICE: Remember, we're businessmen and bankers now.
从前的作为，全是违法勾当
What we do here is illegal.
我们要不留痕迹
We can leave no trace of our activities.
才够格被称为羽毛人
That's why we're called The Feather Men,
因为我们飘来飘去不染污泥
'cause our touch is light.
史派基是高手
THE DON: Now, Spike's a good man.
特种队失去他是一大损失
Day the SAS lost him, they lost a good soldier.
不过他仍认为，他还在特种队
COMMANDER B: Yes, but the problem is he thinks he's still in the SAS.
肮脏的差事总得有人做
Well, someone has to do the dirty work.
我们没人想双手染血
None of us want blood on our pinstripes.
听着，我对血没意见
Listen, I've got no problem with blood.
我担心的是墨水
What worries me is ink.
确定他不会向媒体打小报告？
Make sure he keeps us out of the newspapers.
老板，你好！
MARTIN: What's doing, boss?
你的阿拉伯文很好吗？
Your Arabic's still good, right?
挺不错
Good enough. You're going to Oman.
你去阿曼，我要你去盯一个家伙
I've got a bloke I want you to tail out there.
算你走运！
You lucky bastard!
你真漂亮
You know what? You're gorgeous.
你住哪里？
Where are you staying?
我住希尔顿
I'm staying at the Hilton.
我也是，你住哪间房？
As a matter of fact, so am I. What room are you in?
怎么？你想知道？
Why? Would you like to know?
很想知道
Love to.
你真油嘴滑舌
AIR HOSTESS: You are smooth.
我们来这干嘛？
DAVIES: What are we doing out here, then, in the middle of nowhere?
他就像我们口袋中的小棋
MEIER: Well, I ask him to go hide it, he hides it.
祝我们好运吧！
Could've been your asshole, consider yourself lucky.
闭嘴，麦尔
Shut it, Meier.
感激你，谢了
Appreciate it, thank you.
这瓷砖跟浴室的一样吗？
These tiles are an exact match to the shower step?
百分之百
Hundred percent.
哈里斯到回家
Harris comes home, parks the car. It's been a hard day.
去冲个澡
I'll have a shower. Whoops.
糟糕，他踩到洗发精滑倒
He slips on the shampoo,
后脑勺撞到浴室阶梯
hits the corner of the step with his occiput.
- 全部搞定！ - 少来了
Case closed. Get out of it.
何必大费周章！他搞上有夫之妇
You boys are going about this all wrong. That bird he's screwing is married.
我们干脆轰了他们俩个
Why don't we just pop 'em both and
让一切看来是她老公干的！
make it look like her husband did it.
两个都杀，她做错什么？
Pop 'em both? What's she ever done?
我们只要哈里斯的命
It's Harris we're after.
鲁莽的家伙
Poor bastard.
他只不过是执行命令罢了
Ten years after the war, he cops it for doing something he was ordered to do.
他加入俱乐部时就该明白
He knew what he was doing when he joined the club.
什么俱乐部？
Yeah, what club?
杀人俱乐部
The killing club.
我们也将是
It could be you or me. Yeah, but it's not...
我不是，我没杀过中东人
I'm just glad I never killed a raghead.
开开玩笑，孩子
No offense, my son.
我们动手吧
Let's get this done.
原谅我朋友，他是个超级混蛋
MEIER: Excuse my friend. He's a royal asshole.
该死！
Shit!
他要跑去哪？这里是沙漠耶
DAVIES: Where's he gonna run? It's the middle of the fuckin' desert.
该死！
Son of a...
麦尔
Meier,
在下一个通道堵他
cut him off at the next shaft!
快去！快！
Let's go, let's go.
他人呢？
Where is he?
嘘！
Shh.
快离开这里！搞什么！
DAVIES: Let's get out here. Fuckin' hell!
谁找我们麻烦？
MEIER: So what, now somebody's on our ass?
我们马上离开这
DANNY: We should move right away.
明天准备采访哈里斯
We'll set up Harris' interview for tomorrow.
戴维斯，确保他的妞不会出现
Davies, you make sure his girl doesn't show.
她是无辜的
She has nothing to do with this.
逊咖！
Wanker!
假装要像一点，等等我提问
DANNY: We're military historians. I'll do the talking, all right?
现在应该是五点，对吧？
Well, it's 5:00 somewhere, isn't it?
那这段纪录片要在哪播？
So where's this documentary gonna be shown, then?
电视上？
On the telly?
坐好！
The chair.
哪个单位这么不知好歹！
Those bastards in C Company put this together. Hmm?
搞什么鬼？
HARRIS: What's the matter?
吃到砂子的人叫你们来？
They didn't like sand in their burgers?
哈?，各位！我拒绝发言
Eh? Hello, boys. I'm not saying a word
找我律师来！
till I see my lawyer.
回想一下，库姆村
Think back. The village of Qum.
你杀了一个部落领袖胡笙
You killed a guerilla commander.
你承认吗？
His name was Hussain bin Amr. Do you admit it?
混帐！你是在开玩笑吧？
Fuck off! You're kidding, right?
你在那里指挥一群人
You commanded a company there.
我都指挥一大群人
Yeah, I led a company on that op, sure.
是啊，你暗杀了胡笙
And you assassinated Hussain bin Amr.
现场有目击证人
There were witnesses.
你在他家人面前毙了他
You dropped him in front of his family.
好吧！你说对了，是我干的！
All right, you got me. I did it. Hmm?
去你的！
Fuck you!
快把我放开吧!
Good one. Now untie me.
起来!
Get up.
滚开!
Hey! Piss off!
我们拿到我们要的了
We have what we need.
要是我说是别人毙了他的呢？
What if I told you somebody else dropped your guerilla commander?
那是谁？
His name is...
我记不得人
I can't remember.
但他写了本跟阿曼任务有关的书
But he's writing a book about the whole Oman gig.
你可能找的到
You might find it in there.
如果你识字的话!
If you could read. (LAUGHS)
带去浴室
To the bathroom.
不…等等，等一下!
No, no, no, no. Wait, wait, wait.
我想起来了，看你惊恐的鸟脸
It's coming back to me, looking at your fucking face.
他叫索尔
His name is Captain R. Sole! A-R-S-E H-O-L-E.
闭嘴
Shut up.
你死定了!
You're fucking dead, yeah?
跪下!
On your knees.
一群怪咖!
Fucking queers! Serves you fucking right!
- 低头 - 脏手拿开，怪咖!
Head down. Get your fuckin' hands off me, you queer!
别开玩笑!
You're fuckin' kidding me.
抓住他
DANNY: Hold him still.
别让我逮到，我会把你淹死在马桶
If I find you, I'll put your fuckin' head in the toilet bowl.
好了，受死吧!
Poor fucker.
杰伊！
Jay!
我得搭计程车，轮胎爆了
I need money for the taxi. I had to take a taxi. I had a flat.
去你的!
HARRIS: Fuck you! (SCREAMS)
任务完成
Case closed.
谢谢你
Thank you.
被击沉的船只
WOMAN OVER RADIO: ... tells of a dramatic 12-hour rescue operation
目前正全力抢救中…
to save the crew of Radio Caroline.
雷迪欧号沉没在…
The pirate radio ship sank the...
你做不到的事，你朋友完成了
It seems your friend did what you couldn't.
是我不想做
Wouldn't.
结果都一样，他帮我哥报仇
Wouldn't, couldn't. He's avenged Hussain.
这对你可不是好消息
Good news for the old man, not for you.
这话什么意思？
What do you mean?
三位兄长死去，在沙漠中腐烂
Three brothers dead. Rotting in the sand.
你却不想自己报仇？
You didn't wanna get revenge yourself?
只害怕弄脏自己的手？
Scared of getting your hands dirty?
你最好快习惯
Better get used to it.
要回去的地方没有宫殿
No palace where you're going.
只有帐棚和粪坑
A tent and a hole to shit in.
这个梦魇，即将到来
He's your worst nightmare and he's gonna do it.
那里荒凉，就像监牢
And when he does, you're out of here.
等我发现你在沙漠
When I find you in that desert,
祈祷上帝让我枪法…
I pray God keeps my aim...
准确
...true.
你觉得呢？
Well, what do you think?
是啊，快完成了
Yeah, it's coming along.
你晚餐煮什么？
What are you doing for New Year's Eve dinner?
该死
Oh, shit!
糟了
DANNY: Bollocks!
独居的陌生男子
Strangers are a bit of an
在这里很让人好奇
exotic thing around here.
拜托，这里我很熟
Oh, come on, I didn't think I was a stranger.
你还是很神秘
I know, but you're still exotic.
丹尼，我感觉你有事隐瞒
Danny, something tells me you've got a story to tell.
对
Yeah. Mmm.
你还等什么？派对开始了
Come on, what are you waiting for? Party's outside.
新年快乐！
MAN: Happy New Year!
Happy New Year!
这是这里的传统
It's a tradition around here.
新年快乐…
Happy New Year!
英国  伦敦
前特种员哈里斯，居家意外身亡
该死！
Shit!
你要的米尔巴战役资料
Mirbat. The artist's name is on the back.
自己看着办
Have them talk to him.
还有，我的人在阿曼惹事
One more thing. My boys had some trouble in Oman.
有人在追杀他们
Somebody was tailing them.
我们得仔细调查一下
We'll have to have a look into that, won't we?
是啊
Yeah.
你的画都如此逼真
Ah, that's how you get it so lifelike, then.
什么？
Sorry?
看着照片画，不算作弊吗？
Photos of the lads. Isn't that like cheating?
我精确地重现历史事件
I'm recreating an historical event. Accuracy is everything.
那幅米尔巴之役，让我打冷颤
That Mirbat painting stopped me cold when I saw it.
你也到过那里？
You were at Mirbat?
战友去过，我想你或许也认识
Had a mate there. I was hoping you might have an address for him.
你是特种队员？
You're with the SAS?
以前是
Was.
要找他最好透过特种队
Then your best bet for an address would be Regimental Association...
他们三缄其口
They won't talk to me.
现在没有熟人在里面
Spent the last few years plying my trade overseas. Angola and that.
所以私下来问你
I come to you unofficial like.
等等，我或许有些资料
Well, I might have something somewhere.
给我几分钟吧
Just give me a few minutes.
请便
Be my guest.
有个家伙来打探米尔巴的事
I got a bullshitter askin' about Mirbat.
说是队上的人
Yeah. He claims he's with the regiment.
听口气，感觉一点也不像自己人
No, there's no way he was SAS.
应该是来套话
Yeah, I can smell it off him. Ah, he's a bloody fake.
我的线民电话被切断
My contact says the call was cut off,
不过知道米尔巴，肯定是自己人
but Gowling said that there was somebody there asking about Mirbat. It has to be our guy.
你认为我们该怎么做？
And what would you have us do about it?
尽快找到他，否则会再出人命
Find him.
这应该跟米尔巴之役有关
If we don't, there's gonna be another murder and it will be one of our Mirbat boys.
那他们会是谁？
Then who are they?
他们是专家
Well, they're pros for sure.
这些人敢找上特种队
If these guys are going after the SAS,
一定是最顶尖的专业杀手
they're gonna be top-class professional assassins.
他们背后想必有人主使
They must have a string of hits behind them
不过无法浮上台面
but they're completely under the radar.
我们只有阿曼这个线索
All we've got is Oman.
阿曼！
Oman?
众所皆知，我们的人玩太过火
We all know our people went too far.
阿曼、米尔巴，都该放下仇很
Oman, Mirbat. It all needs to be left alone.
你去告诉那个威尔斯人吧！
You should try telling that to the Welshman.
他说的对
He's right.
找到这个假威尔斯人和他老板
We have to find this phony Welshman and his group.
军事档案指出
DAVIES: The file says an SAS officer
一名军官在米尔巴杀了酋长之子
killed the Sheikh's son at the Battle of Mirbat.
瓦魏克雷格，唯一在场的军官
Warrick Steven Cregg.
杀了所有会动的东西
He was the only officer there that night. Killed everything that moved.
我们下个目标，是真正的高手
He's our worst nightmare. A real hotshot.
这是他的画像
Paintings of him, the lot.
这你哪弄来？
Where did you get this?
画家那里
The bloke who did the paintings.
别担心，他已经被电线缠挂了
Don't you worry about that, all right? He's shuffled off this mortal coil.
这不在计划范围
That wasn't part of the deal.
拜托，凡事总是会有意外
Come on, shit happens when you play in the deep end of the pool, Danny.
为什么不能照计划来？
Why couldn't you two stick to the plan, huh?
锁定克雷格，下一步怎么做？
You've been watching this Cregg, what's your next big idea?
他老婆住院
His wife's in hospital.
他没训练时会待在那里
When he's not training for the selection march, he spends most days there.
我们何不在那里干掉他？
MEIER: So why don't we hit him there?
不行
DANNY: No.
不能在他家人附近
Not near his family.
去打听训练的地点
Get me everything you know on that march.
在那边下手
We'll see where that goes.
调查指出
there's
共有四位米尔巴领导军官
only four Mirbat survivors in Britain.
我找到其他幸存的三人
I've got Locals on the other three.
你去监视他！
You get the celebrity.
瓦魏克雷格？你开玩笑吧！
Warrick Cregg? You're kidding.
希望是场误会
Wish I was.
英国- 航特训练中心
欢迎来到，特勤队地狱选训
DAVIES: Welcome to hell, the SAS selection march.
41英哩，55磅重的装备
Forty-one miles, fifty-five pounds of gear.
每隔几天就会死几个人
They lose someone every couple of years.
根本无从下手
Don't you even think about it.
为什么？
Why not?
选训期间这里都是特种精英
During the march this place is crawling with SAS.
你刚也说，意外随时发生
Yeah, you said it yourself. It's an accident waiting to happen.
那你要怎么逮他？
How are you gonna catch him then?
他训练好几个月了，身手正好
He's been training for months, he's like a greyhound.
让他慢下来就好，不是吗？
We'll just have to slow him down, won't we?
胰岛素、迟缓剂，请签收
Insulin. Chlorpropamide. Initial here.
有啥动静？
Anything doing?
没，克雷格还跟女人在里面
No, Cregg's still in there with his missus.
老大这个给你，让你有精神
Here, boss, this will keep you going.
干杯
Cheers.
潘纳
Pennock.
我要你过来，支援我
I need you back here, mate. Pronto.
你在干嘛？
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
你干嘛？你疯了
靠！给我滚开
Get out of the fucking way!
他是个疯子，小心
不可思议
WOMAN: Maniac!
不敢相信
You wouldn't fucking believe it,
有人也在监视克雷格
somebody was watching Cregg.
什么？
What? Mmm.
你认为是沙漠的杀手同党？
You think he's from the same stable as the shooter in the desert?
身手不错，不过已经太迟了
Maybe. He was good. Whoever he is, he's too late.
很好，用药物拖
Ah, good, good. Chroma slows him down.
胰岛素导致休克
Insulin sends him into shock.
让人体温过低
Hypothermia to you.
你本来打算何时下药？
And when were you planning on getting it to him?
在选训之前
Before the march.
怎么做？那可是特种队基地
How? It's an SAS base, Danny.
你曾在那受过训
That you trained in.
回想整个地方，警戒配置
So think back. The security layout, the lot.
你疯了
You're nuts.
你要动手吗？
Are you gonna do it?
你真的是个超级大疯子
Man, you really are one crazy son of a bitch, Danny.
英国  航特选训中心
没时间了，你剩不到一分钟
Clock's ticking. You've got under a minute, all right?
有人来了
We've got company.
今晚真不错
Lovely night.
你不能停在这
You can't stop here, mate.
我没停，是卡车故障
I didn't stop, the truck did.
你不搞定它，我们就搞你
If you don't fucking move it, we will.
好啦！可是它漏油
All right, all right. But it's pissing oil, mate.
我没办法
There's nothing I can do about it.
把收音机关掉
Turn off the bloody radio.
你的工具呢？
MAN: Where's your gear?
准备！快上车！
Right. On the trucks!
我不管你是哪个军团
SERGEANT 1: I don't care what regiment you're from.
不管你自以为有多行
I don't care how great you think you are.
让我看你有什么能耐，臭娘们！
Let's see what you're made of, ladies.
快上车
On the trucks.
快点
SERGEANT 2: Come on!
动作快
Get moving, you lot.
只有用一半的剂量
He only got half the dose.
这够吗？
Is it enough?
药效快发作了，盯紧他
MEIER: Enough? He's a dead man walking. Stay on him, okay?
他的名字叫萨林
DANNY: His name was Salim bin Amr.
你记得是你动手杀他吗？
Do you remember the name?
想清楚，你杀了他吗？
Did you kill him?
对，是我杀的
Think back.
我宰了那混蛋，又怎样？
Did you kill him, Major? CREGG: Yeah, I did. I did the bastard. So bloody what?
丹尼不想这么做
Danny didn't want to do this.
你做的？
DANNY: You did?
你儿子也不想回去沙漠
And your boy doesn't want to go back to the desert.
国防部长遗憾宣布…
TV BROADCASTER: The Ministry of Defence today announced the death of an army officer during maneuvers.
33岁瓦魏克雷格少校
Thirty-three-year-old, Major Warrick Steven Cregg,
在特种队训练中死于意外
died of exposure during an SAS exercise on the Brecon Beacons.
当时的天候很糟…
Weather conditions at the time were described as appalling, with...
请放尊重一点
Show a bit of respect, lads.
百发百中！
Top that.
我带礼物来了
I come bearing gifts.
安静!
Oi!
只是一点小小心意
AGENT: From my boys in Angola.
我希望你会喜欢这食物
I have no idea how you're meant to eat this.
是谁在盯我们？
Who's on our ass?
是我！不用担心
I'm on it. Don't worry.
只剩一个人头
Look, there's only one more to go.
在这之后，我就让你们接轻松的
After this is done, I'll get you boys a nice, cushy job in the sun.
这是最后一次
There is no "after this."
我是头兀鹰，依附杀手过活
I'm a vulture. I live off killers.
你的想法很独特
It gives me a unique perspective.
听说过宿命吗？就在你身上!
Have you heard of the two percent? That's you.
戴维斯、特勤队，你们全部
Davies, the SAS, all you lot.
特务、杀手或是英雄
Mercenaries, hit men, heroes.
你们都是天生杀手命
You're all part of that two percent of men who are natural killers.
所以你永远逃不了
That's why you'll never get out.
你无法违背你的天性，丹尼
You can't run away from who you are, Danny.
那不是我，我也没做那些事
That's not who I am, that's what I've done.
我可以做别的
And I can do something else.
是啊，那样听来不错
Yeah, yeah.
不过我们先解决正事吧！
That's all nice and good. But let's just take care of business first, shall we?
你第三个目标，赛门迈肯少校
Your third target, Major Simon McCann,
人称 疯狗赛门
Mad Simon McCann of late.
你怎么找他的？
How'd you find him?
四处打听，这很简单
Asked around. It was easy.
他现在成了垃圾佣兵
These days, he's your basic "cash for trash" mercenary.
他很容易搞定
He's a sitting duck.
我刚刚不是说带礼物来吗？
Now didn't I tell you I came bearing gifts?
你知道哪能找到他
You know where to find me.
别相信那家伙？满口谎话
DAVIES: You don't trust that snake, do you?
是吗？你怎么知道？
He's lying. Yeah? How do you know?
他的嘴唇在发抖
His lips were moving.
他献上第三个目标
He just gave us a third target.
你就不用再费心思
You've done nothing on that last file.
有人盯上我们
Someone's onto us.
我要救杭特，我要结束此事
I want Hunter out of there.
拿到钱后我要享受一下
I want this finished. And I want to be around to enjoy the money when it is.
你该先买一对蛋蛋！
The first thing you should buy is a pair of balls.
准备去猎杀迈肯吧！
We're going after McCann, all right?
我好想你
ANNE: I miss you.
我对你还不熟，但我好想你
There's a lot I don't know about you, but I do know that much.
我说服自己一切都很好
I convince myself that everything's okay
因为我跟你一起时，我很快乐
because when I'm with you I'm happy.
但当你离开后
But then you go away
我发现对你好陌生
and I realize that I know nothing about you.
不知道你去哪，去做什么？
I don't know where you go and I don't know what you do,
我在想
I mean,
你有另一个人生
you've got a whole another life, Danny.
有别段感情？
Is there someone else?
拜托，安
Come on, Anne.
不然呢？
Well, then, what is it?
天哪！你有什么没告诉我？
I mean, Jesus, what are you not telling me?
你在隐藏什么？
What are you hiding?
能不能等我回去再谈？
Can we talk about this when I get back?
我恨你！
To hell with it.
干！
Fuck.
怎样？
What?
有位英雄丹尼，也难过美人关…
You show me a beautiful woman, I'll show you a bloke that's sick of her shit.
闭嘴啦
Shut up.
承认吧！
Roger that.
那就是他？
DANNY: That him?
就是他
DAVIES: That's him.
疯狗赛门
Major Simon McCann.
一直在苏丹服役，四年前退休
Served in the Sultan's forces till he was pensioned out four years ago.
再来一台
And another.
你在搞什么鬼？
Oi!
滚开啦，老头
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
尝点拳头？
Piss off, grandpa. You want some?
看来不像受过伤
DANNY: Doesn't look like an invalid.
当时，一枚炸弹在他车下爆炸
Like I said, a bomb went off under his jeep,
炸坏了他的神经
scrambled his wiring.
他无法工作，但是个疯子
He can't keep a job. He's a fucking psycho.
天哪
Jesus.
好了，够了
Come on, mate, that's enough.
他在这干嘛？
What's he doing here?
那就是我在医院遇到的人
That's the one I went head-to-head with at the hospital.
是哦
Right.
等等…
Wait, wait, wait.
走
Let's go.
跟踪他
Stick with him.
老迈，是我，你还好吗？
Mac, it's me. You okay?
在修理挡路的小混混
McCANN: Oh, yeah, still scraping skinheads off my doorstep.
好吧，只是确认一下
All right, mate. I was just checking in.
开绿色跑车，他是谁？
Bloke who drives that green Jag, what's his name?
他叫史派基洛根，被军中辞退
AGENT: His name's Spike Logan. He's an ex-soldier of some kind.
某次逞英雄时眼睛中枪
He got his eye shot out playing a hero somewhere.
他目前无业，怪里怪气的
He's got no job and he keeps odd hours.
没有其他资料吗？
Don't you know who these guys are?
你不是最会打探秘密？
I mean, secrets being your bread and butter.
不用担心
Don't worry about it.
我很担心，你也该担心
I do worry about it. You should, too.
我的人一有行动，他们就出现
Every move my guys make, these lot are waiting.
我想你该找几个人逼问一下
You ask me, I think it's time you put those fancy shoes of yours on a few throats.
是吗！也没人来逼问你
Yes. But no one is asking you.
你来信应征保全职缺，迈肯先生
DAVIES: You'll be interviewing for a security position, Mr. McCann.
对！
McCANN: Right.
其实是特种队的朋友介绍你
Actually we got your name from a mutual friend in the SAS.
是吗，真的？
Yeah, really?
那我们就周二10点见
So, we'll see you Tuesday the 17th, at 10:00.
好
Okay.
期待那一天的到来
We look forward to it.
到时候见
See you then.
就这么说定
All right, my son.
他会到
He'll be there.
很好！
Good.
小意思！
I don't get it.
迈肯住这里
McCann lives here.
他周二10点会来面谈
He'll be here for the interview, Tuesday at 10:00.
他会走这条路
He'll take this road.
波士顿路，太赞了！
The Boston Brakes. Perfect.
波士顿马路崎山区
They weren't perfect in Boston.
三不管地带
I wasn't at the controls.
还有十天
We've got 10 days.
十天？
MEIER: Ten days?
越快搞定此事越好
The quicker we get this done, the better.
我需要找些帮手
I'm going to need to bring in some help.
好吧！
Okay. DAVIES: "Okay." Just like that?
就这样？迈肯受到严密监控
McCann's being watched.
你要怎么让他招认？
How are you gonna get a confession out of him?
我们没要他招，造假就好
We aren't. We'll fake it.
灯光和摄影弄烂一点，就可以了
Bit of bad lighting and camera work, you could be him.
我们只要在报告中做手脚就好
What we'll do is play back what he admitted to in the reports.
你是谁？
Who are you?
这国家能带枪上直升机的
I'm the one they let fly around in an unmarked chopper
只有我一个
with a gun in my pocket.
你可以叫我老大
You can call me MFWIC.
老大？
"MFWIC"?
我就是他妈的老大！
Mother Fucker What's In Charge.
我们有个问题
We have questions.
关于这个非法聚会- 羽毛人俱乐部
About this little illegal club of yours, The Feather Men.
你的打手，该现身了吧？
Your attack dog, time to bring him to heel, eh?
到时我们会安排
And then we'll put that on the agenda.
各位
Gentlemen.
请稍候一下
We'll be with you in a minute.
我要派人全天候盯着迈肯少校
I want to put Locals on Major McCann around the clock.
我知道迈肯是你的老朋友
I realize McCann is an old friend of yours,
可是他跟此事有咯关？
but what has it to do with us?
这样你们才能逮住凶手
But this is our chance to get the bastards who killed Cregg and Harris.
政府当局找不到他杀证据
The authorities found no evidence of foul play in either case.
你说什么没证据？我这里就有
What are you talking about, "No evidence?" I've got the evidence right here.
每个人都知道他们是被谋杀的
Everybody in this room knows that those men were killed.
大家都知道迈肯就是下一个
Everybody knows that McCann is going to be next.
够了，史派基
That's enough, Spike.
我们得采取行动
We have to do something.
我们可以进行表决
THE DON: Well, we could put it to the vote.
对，可是那得全体委员出席
Yes, but that would require the full committee.
需要一点时间
And it will have to wait.
史派基
Spike. That was a set-up.
那是陷阱！把他派去往陷阱跳！
He sent him away. He knew there'd be a vote.
史派基，拜托
Spike, please. Look, listen.
听着，事情超乎想像
This is getting big.
上级在质疑，我们倍感压力
The powers that be are asking questions. Pressure's being applied.
他们要保护自己的名声
They have their reputations to protect.
我了解名声的重要性
I'm not doing this to protect reputations.
我会处理这事情
You know, a light touch is one thing,
可是要完全不碰？我做不到
but no touch at all? I can't do this.
你知道此事不被认可
You realize this thing is set up for maximum deniability?
线民是你找的
You're the only one who knows the Locals.
他们只听你下达的命令
All their orders come through you.
所以呢？
So?
这事要是曝光，死的就是你
So? If this comes out, you're the one who takes the fall.
怎么死？
Fall? From where?
我已经受够那些委员
I am done with this whole committee thing.
我自己去找他
I'm gonna find him.
他虽然只是个孩子，但很有潜力
MEIER: He's a good kid, don't worry. I'm shtupping his mom.
他知道他的任务吧！
DAVIES: Does he know he can't bring his mom on the job?
知道、知道
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
向阿曼的孤魂打声招呼
DAVIES: Tell your mates in Oman I said hello.
丹尼，我有点紧张？
Danny, is this what it was like when you were first starting?
这是你第一次？天哪
This is your first job? Jesus.
我第一次杀人，吐了一天
My first time, I puked for a day afterwards.
我当时年轻又蠢，跟他们没两样
I was young and dumb, just the way the army likes them. I could be good at this, man.
我可以轻松了结这人吧？
I mean, it's easy, yeah?
杀人很简单
Killing's easy.
承受这一切活着才困难
Living with it is the hard part.
要是我看到他，我会通知你
PORTER: If I see him, I'll give you a bell.
不必害怕传话出去
Don't be shy about spreading the word.
找到的人都有重赏
There's a very tidy finder's fee.
我会睁大眼睛找
I'll keep my eyes peeled.
剩一个，今晚是关键
One more and we'll call it a night.
生意上门
JAKE: We're on.
他迟到了
MEIER: He's late.
保持75尺，安全距离范围
Just keep me at 75 feet
好
and give me a clear line of sight. Yeah, okay.
哪来的烂司机!
Where'd you buy your license?
跟紧他，小心点
On his tail. Doing 60.
一分钟内你就能看到丹尼
You'll have a visual on Danny in one minute.
盯紧他，杰克
Stay with him, Jake.
我找到他了
I got him.
目标入笼
DAVIES: We have target in sight.
我会悼念他的
JAKE: Gonna miss it.
快切进去，快点，切进去！
Come on, get in. Get in behind him!
空间不够
Just do it, get in! There's not enough room!
逼他
Push him!
我没办法卡位
I can't get in there.
那就超车！快！
Okay, then overtake him. Go! Pass him!
麦尔，你在干嘛？
DAVIES: What the hell are you doing, Meier?
我需要距离倒数
MEIER: I need a range countdown.
麦尔，别搞砸了
Meier: Don't screw this up.
我直接倒车
I'll operate looking backwards.
别激动
Relax, Meier.
戴维斯会帮你倒数
Davies will give you the countdown.
四百公尺
DAVIES: 400 meters.
好，帮我看路
MEIER: Okay, range me.
三百公尺
300 meters.
走外线，麦尔
Outside lane, Meier.
二百公尺
200 meters.
他来了
Here he comes.
剩一百公尺
100 meters.
现在！就是现在！
Now, now. Now, Meier! Shut up!
闭嘴啦！
Now, Meier!
甩尾
Fishtail! Fishtail!
你成功了！
JAKE: You fucking got him!
- 马的！ - 他死了，他死翘翘了
You got him, man. MEIER: Oh, fuck, he's dead. He's dead as Elvis.
大功告成
You got him, man!
停车！
Stop the car.
我们要确认目标死亡
We gotta be sure Elvis has left the building.
目标有人监控！赶快离开！
DAVIES: Target had a minder. Head to the exit point.
引他过来
Bring him to me.
他有人保护
He had a fucking minder. Fuck!
靠，被看到！
You got him, man. You got him!
闭嘴啦！开车！快！
Shut up! Drive! Go! Go! Go!
他是谁？
Who is he?
我不知道，状况回报
I don't know. Give me an update, Davies.
他追上来了！
Oh, man, he's coming fast!
那里有院子，左转进去
Up here there's a yard. Take a left. Shit! Up here to the left. Keep going.
坐稳了！
Hold on.
呼叫，戴维斯
Come in, Davies.
戴维斯，你跑哪去了？
Davies, where the fuck are you?
逮到你了，混帐东西
Got you, you bastards.
去他的！快！快！
MEIER: Fuck this! Go! Go!
来了、他来了！
JAKE: Here he comes! Here he comes!
下车
Get out of the car!
你谁派来的？
Where the fuck do you guys come from?
- 站远一点 - 别激动
Step away from the car. Easy.
- 杰克！ - 别激动
Jake. Yeah?
检查车子！慢慢来！
Take it easy. Check the car. Slowly.
不、不！
No, no, no, no!
不！
No!
没身份证
He had no ID. Nothing.
这家伙是谁？
Not a fucking thing.
在搞什么！
Who the fuck is he?
到底在搞什么！
This shouldn't have happened.
别激动，丹尼
This should not have fucking happened! Take it easy, Danny.
丹尼
Danny...
别激动？
Take it easy?
愚蠢的笨蛋，多此一举！
We were out of there. Clean. Done.
坎贝没回应，你那边呢？
PENNOCK: Look, I'm getting nothing. Campbell's not picking up.
- 靠 - 没消息但这里有辆烧焦的车
Ls there anything at your end? Fuck.
这些混帐东西是谁？
Who are these bastards?
不知道，不过他们在找失踪的人
I don't know. But they're looking for their man and they're not legit.
杰克，打这个号码
Jake, call this number.
告诉探员我们需要潜逃出境
Tell the Agent we need a cleanup crew here ASAP.
还有把无线电接上我的车
And wire that radio into my car.
我来打吧
Gimme here.
该结束了吧！
That's it then.
没错！
Yeah.
丹尼
Done.
我今晚飞走，你也该走
I fly tonight.
他们追上来了
You should get going, too. They're close.
麦尔那份呢？
What happens to Meier's cut?
就送给其他人
There has to be somebody.
可怜的家伙，我会帮他烧栋房
Poor sod. I'll have a hooker for him. He'd like that. (CHUCKLES)
好
Yeah.
小心点
Be safe.
你也是
You too, Davies.
我还在找坎贝，情况不妙
PENNOCK: Sorry. We 're still looking for Campbell, but it looks bad.
谢谢，还有什么需要…
Thank you, sir. If there's anything else...
客房服务，要带点情色
Room service. Something exotic.
怎样？
Yeah?
我找到你的威尔斯人了
PORTER: I found your Welshman
你确定是他？
You sure it's him?
千真万确！
I'm sure.
去他的！
(SCREAMING) Fucking hell!
起来，穿衣服
Get up. Get dressed. Move!
快点，起来
Look... Get up!
别告诉任何人，你懂吗？
Don't say a word to anyone. Do you understand?
你杀了赛门迈肯，对吧？
You killed Simon McCann, didn't you?
还有坎贝，他人呢？
Yeah? And Campbell. Where is he, you fucker?
没听过他
Never heard of him.
你就这点能耐？
That all you got?
我们逮到那个威尔斯人了
Yeah, Spike? We got the Welshman.
我们现在就带他回去
We 're bringing him to you now. Over.
很好，潘纳，干的好
SPIKE: Nice work, Pennock. Well done.
我很期待见见这个王八蛋
I'm looking forward to meeting the bastard.
我要切断你老二喂鲨鱼，喜欢吗？
Hey, Spike's gonna cut your dick off and shove it in your mouth. You like that?
听起来不错
I like the sound of that, yeah.
- 是吗？ - 是啊
Do you? Yeah, I do.
给我上车，上车
Get in the van.
快点，上车
Get in. Come on, get in!
靠，敢耍我，上车！
Fuck me. You're kidding. Come on. Get in!
好了，混帐东西
There you are, you prick.
别挡路，笨蛋
- 打开 - 滚开
Open up.
等等
老板？
Boss.
要我看一具死尸！
What am I meant to do with that?
他身上有这个
He had this on him.
电话号码，干的好
A phone number. Great work.
我是要逼问活口，不要整团烂泥
That pile of mincemeat was our best chance of finding out who these bastards are.
处理掉他，还有追踪那个号码
Print him and trace that bloody number.
一群笨蛋！
You fucking idiots!
别动！
DANNY: Drop it.
把枪，放地上
Left hand. Put the gun on the floor.
踢过来
Kick it to me.
那个威尔斯人，他人呢？
The Welshman, they were bringing him to you. Where is he?
他死了
He didn't make it.
是你？你干的？
You? You do it?
一辆卡车，他挡到它了
A truck. He made a break for it.
他很走运
He got lucky.
车已经开很慢
Would have been very slow otherwise.
那是我朋友
Yeah, well that was my fucking friend.
是吗？迈肯是我朋友，还有…
Yeah, and McCann was mine. And what about fucking...
坎贝吗？
Campbell?
不是
No.
戴维斯、麦尔、哈里斯
Davies. Meier. Harris.
迈肯、克雷格、坎贝，阎王正忙着
McCann. Cregg. Campbell. Too many names on that list.
不要加上你的名字，史派基
Don't go adding yours, Spike.
进去！
Inside.
你是谁？
Who are you?
不重要
Doesn't matter.
今晚之后，我就不存在了
After tonight, I don't exist.
那是什么意思？
What the fuck is that supposed to mean?
一切都将结束
It's over.
你这么想？
Done. You think so?
没制服、没战争、不再牵挂
No uniform, no war, not special.
忘记自己是谁
You don't know what to do with yourself.
过着没有羁绊的人生
Nobody knows what to do with you.
错了
Right? Wrong.
你知道我的名字，你逃不了
You know my name but you don't know me.
你根本不知道我多厉害
You have no idea who you're fucking with.
真的？
Really?
别吓我
Don't follow me.
别让我再遇到你！
Don't put your name on that list.
第三份口供
The third confession.
凶手全都已经被杀
SHEIKH AMR: The killers have been killed,
现在你可以回沙漠了
now you can go home.
你可以把人带走了
BAKHAIT: You can have your man.
确认过后，会把钱给你
You will get the money when it's been checked.
带他出来
Bring him out.
Bring him out!
让我…戴上我的表
Let me put... I just wanna put my watch on.
怎么回事？
What's the matter with you?
- 你还好吧？ - 还好
You all right? Yeah.
有何计划？
What's the plan?
我们离开这里
Get out of here.
好，听来不错
Okay, sounds good.
我本来以为你死定了
I was sure you were gonna get yourself killed, kiddo.
你怎么做到的？怎么成功的？
How in the hell did you do it? How'd you pull it off?
我不想谈
I don't want to talk about it.
我明白，不过谢谢你
I get it.
不是为我，而是为我的孩子
Thank you. Not from me, but from my kids
让他们还能有一个老爸
for having a dad.
感激之情，我无以回报
I could never thank you enough for what you did. Never.
你可以，你可以退出这行
Yeah, you can.
不要再干这行
You can get out of the business. Be done with this shit.
不再杀手，不再干特务
No more soldiering. No more mercenary work.
好吧，好
All right. Okay, okay.
我求你，告诉我你不干了
I'm asking you, please. Tell me you're done.
我不干了，不干了
I'm done. I'm out.
很好，别再踏进来了
Good.Stay out.
不然这一切就没意义
Otherwise all this is for nothing.
洋基队战绩如何？
So, how are the Yankees doing?
你可以先打电话来
You could have called.
你不会接
You wouldn't have answered.
是不会，很抱歉
No. Sorry about that.
你抱歉？该抱歉的是我
You're sorry? It's me who should be sorry.
工作结束了吗？你要走了？
So it's over? You going back again?
不
No.
你准备告诉我一切了？
And you're ready to tell me everything?
你想知道什么都行
Whatever you want to know.
很好!
Good.
只不过我已经不想知道…
Except I don't want to know. Not anymore.
我很想念你，丹尼
I've missed you, Danny.
我不在乎过去，只在乎现在
I don't really care about the past, I just care about now.
老板
Hey, boss.
怎样？
All right, Cal?
那个号码
That phone number?
那是间公司
That was a business.
那是一家旅行社
It's for some shit travel agent.
帮忙安排特务进出世界各地
Runs mercenaries in and out of every shithole in the world.
进来!
Come in.
你好!
Hello?
喂，丹尼
AGENT: Hello, Danny.
你怎么会有这个号码？
How'd you get this number?
拜托，别侮辱我的专业能力
Please, Danny, don't insult my professionalism.
你要做什么？
What do you want?
任务出状况
We got a problem with the job.
任务早完成了
The job's done. No.
没有，你杀错人
You killed the wrong guy.
还有一个要解决
There's one more to go.
我费尽心血才找到元凶
I busted my nuts setting this job up
我要分一成佣金
and I want my 10%.
不，我已经做完我该做的
No, I did what I had to do.
去跟酋长说吧，他要跟你见面
Tell that to the Sheikh. He wants a London meet with his son.
如果不想来，当心你女友
Check with your girlfriend before you make any rash decisions. Eh?
你在干嘛？快来睡觉
What are you doing? Come to bed.
跟我来，安
Come with me, Anne.
什么？
What?
去巴黎
To Paris.
我去伦敦，你到那里等我
You can wait for me there while I'm in London.
明天就去，你不喜欢这里吗?
Leave tomorrow. Nothing's keeping you here, right?
现在是半夜，太仓促了
It's the middle of the night. Anne. Anne!
安，他们知道你的事
They know about you.
谁知道我的事?
Who knows about me?
还有我们的事
And about us.
何时才能平静？
When will this be over?
很快
Soon.
只要一切顺利
If all goes well.
会顺利吧？
It will, won't it?
丹尼
Danny.
帮我照顾她
Keep a good eye on her, huh?
听着，别自己单枪匹马去
Listen, don't do this on your own.
没别的办法
No other way.
戴维斯、麦尔，都是落单遇难
Davies, Meier, all this heat on you.
拜托，我们上车去伦敦吧
Come on, let's just get in the car, we'll go to London,
去机场，就这样
be at the airport...
不行，我们讲好的，记得吗？
No. We have a deal, remember?
我也想了断！
What do you mean? You think I can't cut this, is that it?
而且，我不是保母，拜托
I mean, I'm not a babysitter, come on!
我要她安全无虞，我只信任你
I need to know she's safe.
这太扯了，你可以落跑
You're the only one I trust. This is bullshit. You could run, both of you just go, come on.
总会被找到的，你很清楚
Everyone gets found. You know that.
你会送命的，小子
You're gonna get yourself killed, kiddo.
万事拜托
Thanks for doing this.
别开玩笑了！
You gotta be kidding me.
欢迎回到伦敦，先生
Welcome back to London, sir. Thank you, sir.
告诉老家伙，敢威胁她就死定了
You tell the old man he threatens her again, I'll put it between his eyes.
哈里斯，在影片中他说
Harris, the pilot, on his film he said
是别的士兵杀了我哥
another soldier killed my brother.
他是想误导我们，他认为那很好玩
He was winding us up. He thought it was some kind of a joke!
这书刚刚出版
This was just published.
作者曾在特种部队服役
The author served with the SAS.
他说他曾埋伏杀死部落领袖
He describes an ambush where he killed a guerilla leader.
哈里斯没杀胡笙
Harris did not kill Hussain.
你胡乱给个名字，就说他有罪
You gave me his name. You said he was guilty.
那是阿拉的旨意
Such is Allah's will.
阿拉个头！
Allah's will?
你让我杀了一个无辜的人
You had me kill an innocent man.
这本书是真正凶手的自白
The book will be the real killer's confession.
现在我父亲需要！
My father...
我知道你父亲需要什么
I know what your father needs.
我要洛夫芬宁的所有资讯
I need everything you can get on a Ranulph Fiennes.
对，作家，前特种队员
Yeah, writer, ex-SAS.
精准旅行，需要我效劳吗？
你找到什么？
What you got?
我找到芬宁
I got Fiennes.
他还在阿曼促销他的书
He's still pushing his book on Oman.
他星期二要开媒体茶会
He'll be doing a press bash on Tuesday.
星期二？
Tuesday. I know it's a bit short notice,
时间有点短，人不好找
but I'll be able to put a crew together. Nah.
不用，我自己来
I'll do this on my own.
你确定？我打几通电话…
Danny, are you sure? It's just a phone call.
我想他上钩了
I guess he's sure.
宾他妈的果
B-I-N-G fucking O.
我就知道能找到你，混帐东西
I knew I'd find you, you bastard.
我能坐下吗？
Do you mind if I sit down?
你看起来很孤单
You look lonely.
你是丹尼的朋友
You're Danny's friend.
有名的杭特
The famous Hunter.
他有说我好话吗？
He say nice things?
你在这里干嘛？
What are you doing here?
照顾你
Watching you.
你该跟着他
You should be with him.
我试过，没用
I tried. It didn't work.
他要我保护你
He wanted me here to protect you.
而你看来也需要被保护
And you look like you needed protecting.
保护什么？
From what?
你
You.
你认为他不会回来，还有未来的事
You're thinking about him not coming back. What happens then?
没有，我…
No, I...
我有老婆，我知道那个表情
I have a wife, I know the look.
我和丹尼患难相知
We've known each other through thick and thin, Danny and I.
我老婆琳赛爱他，我的孩子们爱他
Celine, my wife, she loves him, my kids love him.
连小狗也爱丹尼
I mean, wild animals like Danny.
我知道丹尼会为了你回来
I know Danny's going to come back for you.
等他回来，你就会夺走他
And when he does, you're going to steal him away. Huh?
我不知道这是怎样
I don't know what the plan is.
先生
是，先生
- 来一瓶红酒吧？ - 马上来
我现在要审讯一名女性
I have a woman to interrogate now.
好，不错嘛
PENNOCK: All right, look alive, lads.
各位
Boys.
这家伙很行，非常厉害
So this guy is good. Very good.
惊觉有状况，就会落跑
If he senses something's up,
碰到他，马上反击
he'll run until you corner him and then he fights.
毫不留情的攻击
But now the gloves are off.
今天就是他的忌日
This all fucking ends today.
好了，大家都知道规矩
MARTIN: All right, everybody knows the rules.
就是不守规矩！
MAN: There are no rules.
他从前门进来，大鱼入网
MAN: Boss, he's out front. I think we're on.
黑皮衣，应该是他
This could be him. Black leathers.
知道了
Roger that.
他刚走买梯，肯定就是
He just took the service stairs. It has to be him.
别轻举妄动，很快就知道了
Just hold your positions. We'll know soon enough.
他昏倒了，我们逮到他了
He's down, boss. We got him! He stays alive.
留活口，我到之前别碰他
Pennock, don't you touch him until I'm there.
待在那里
Stay here.
别乱动，混蛋
Stay there, you fucker.
拿掉他的安全帽
Get his helmet off before he chokes.
该死！
Shit.
手举高！靠着墙
Hands high, against the wall.
好，别乱来
Okay, easy with that.
各位，我们的人挂了！他在屋顶
Guys, our man's down. Head for the roof.
潘纳！右边屋顶
Pennock, head for the roof.
正准备上去，老板
We're on our way up now, boss.
头！快点！
Come on, move!
他跳楼！到别栋了！
He jumped! He jumped!
快点！他逃了，快点！
PENNOCK: Come on, come on, he's on the move. Let's go!
潘纳？
SPIKE: Pennock?
别声张！
Don't you do it.
他不在上面
PENNOCK: There's no sign of him up here, boss.
这边只有河，他消失了
I can see all the way to the river. He's gone.
该死
Shit.
敢乱动，你就死了
Move and you're dead.
好了，快点
Right, let's go, let's go.
进去
Get in.
怎么会这样？
What is this?
那是为了坎贝
PENNOCK: That's for Campbell.
还有为了克雷格
And that's for Cregg.
你玩够没？
SPIKE: You finished?
我们根本还没开始
We haven't even started.
把罩子拿掉
Take the hood off.
在外面等着
Wait outside, boys.
留一点给我们，老板
Save a little bit for us, boss.
他为何还活着？为何没杀他？
So why is he still alive? Why didn't you kill him?
那是你会做的事
Is that what you would have done?
你们这群伪君子
I thought you were the good guys.
你又是谁？为谁效命？
Who are you? Who do you work for?
你我有很多共通点
You and I got a lot in common.
真的？你这么想？
Really? You think so?
但你被绑在椅子上
So, you're sitting there, tied to a chair
而我手上拿着枪
and I'm standing here with a gun in my hand.
请你告诉我这是怎么回事！
Now you tell me what the fuck this was all about.
怎么回事？
"Was?"
以为这样就能结束？
You think this is over?
能什么事？
There'll be somebody else.
你的人还有芬宁，全死定了！
Your boy, Fiennes, is gonna die.
扣板机吧，杀了我他也难活
Go on, pull the trigger. Kill me and you kill Fiennes.
他们没找到他是不会罢休的
They won't stop till they get him.
我能阻止你，也能阻止他们
I stopped you, I'll stop them.
我并不想杀他，但他们很想
I didn't want to kill him. They will.
把那交给对的人，这事就结束了
You put that in the right hands, this thing's over.
照片？为什么？
The camera? Why?
证明，他死了的证据
Proof. Evidence that he's dead.
这是唯一救他的办法
It's the only way you'll save him.
放我走，我就告诉你幕后指使者
You tell me I'll walk, I'll tell you who's behind this and where to find him.
好，你走
Okay. You walk.
以萨酋长
Sheikh Amr bin Issa.
你能在阿曼找到他
You'll find him in Oman.
为什么？
Why?
石油掠夺！
The war.
他们杀了他三个儿子
They killed three of his sons.
休想
No.
人还真好啊！
Some good guy, eh?
别动！
Drop it.
进去
Inside.
在他旁边，跪下
Beside him. On your knees.
你被陷害了
You were set up.
这就是我们喜欢你的原因
That's what we love about you lot.
你只在乎行动
You only care about the action.
从没想过为何或为谁而战
Never think about what you might really be fighting for. Or who.
不深入调查内幕
Never see the big picture.
被陷害的是你，他只是绊脚石
You're the one that was set up. He just wouldn't get out of the way.
女王陛下不喜欢秘密组织
Her Majesty's government doesn't like secret societies.
特别是阻挡我们利益的组织
Particularly when they get in the way of our interests.
知道那烂沙漠里蕴涵多少石油吗？
Do you know how much oil that pathetic crust of desert is floating on?
开采出来后市值多少钱吗？
Do you know what those contracts are worth?
三条人命
Three men's lives.
可不是吗
That's right.
不错
所以我们送杀手进去
We deliver the killers.
只要等小儿子回家
Son Number 4 goes home
石油顺利开采，我们就能获利
and when Sheikhy re-ups the contracts, we get favorable consideration.
你这个混蛋！你…
A bargain. You bastard, you're a...
这叫爱国
Patriot.
那三个死人为国效命
Who serves his country as those three men did with their deaths.
你将追随他们
As you will with yours.
我的妈呀！
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
怎样？
回来！
她在那里
AGENT: There she is.
丹尼漏掉的小绵羊
Danny might've dropped off the radar,
但有件事很确定，他会回来找她
but one thing's for sure. He'll come back for her.
他会带着六百万来赎她
He'll come through that door with $6 million
而她将会消失
and she won't be there.
一成的佣金！别忘了
Who don't you screw out of his 10%? Yours truly.
老板
Boss.
处理他
Deal with him.
这无关个人恩怨，纯粹生意
It wasn't personal. Just business.
你竟敢耍我们，追究原因
You played us. I don't care why.
要是真有需要宰掉谁，肯定你
But if ever a lying piece of shit needed killing, it was you.
任务结束
Game's over.
你知道我不会伤害她
You know, I wouldn't have hurt her.
我只要我的钱，她只是担保品
I just wanted my cut. She was only collateral.
你敢再找他们
If you go after them,
我会找到你，用尽一切方法
I'll find you. Remember, everybody gets found.
砍你人头！
Even you.
你把照片给那个老混蛋
HUNTER: You gotta get those photos to that old bastard
然后了结这一切？
to finish this thing for good, you hear, kiddo?
所以我才来，你呢？
That's why I'm here. What about you?
保母生涯结束
Babysitting's over, kiddo.
谁说的？
Who says? I say.
她很安全，现在换照顾你
She's safe. You're the one taking the chances now.
拜托
Come on. "Come on?"
拜托？你上次就踏入了陷阱
You walked into a trap last time.
你以为我还会让你这么做吗？
You think I'm going to let you do that again?
我跟你女朋友说过你会回来
I told your girl you were going to be coming back to her.
你要害我变成骗子吗？
You want to make a liar out of me?
你应该要保护她，不是访问她
You know, you were supposed to be guarding her, not interviewing her.
我很爱跟美女搭讪，这我不否认
Well, I was always a sucker for a pretty face, no denying that.
但她啥都没说，口风很紧
She's a keeper, that's for sure.
她并不知道内幕吧？
She doesn't know, does she?
猜到一些
Some. Yeah.
事情会很难搞
It's going to be tough. My old man used to say,
我老爸说：人生就像玫瑰花
"Life's like licking honey from a thorn."
那是什么意思？
Yeah, what does that mean?
美丽却带刺
Something about good times and bad times.
看来我们遇上的都是野玫瑰
Seems like it's been all thorns for us lately. Both of us.
好，是该做个了断
All right, let's finish this.
我掩护你
I'll be top cover.
要是有状况，我就冲进去
Anything goes wrong,
酋长想完结此事，送照片后就走
I'm coming in. Hey, look, the Sheikh wants this over. It's in, hand over the photos, and out.
是吗？
Yeah? Yeah.
对，不会有问题的
There isn't going to be a problem.
要保持警觉
From your mouth to God's ears.
听我号令，别轻举妄动
Don't move till I give the all-clear, okay?
你是谁？你要什么？
BAKHAIT: Who are you? What do you want?
给酋长的
For the Sheikh.
我要看到他亲自拿到手
I have to see it placed in his hands.
把这些拿回部落
Take these to my people.
给他们看我赢回荣耀
Show them what I have done.
我想跟酋长说说话
I have a message for the Sheikh.
他还活着
He's still alive.
你上当了
They're fakes.
你在地狱找不到他
But this is going to end.
死了也罢！
I don't care.
我不在乎，谁想回去那个烂沙漠
What'll I do in that godforsaken desert?
你是不是忘了什么？
Haven't you forgotten something?
等等，先别动
HUNTER: Hold it, hold it, stay where you are.
有状况
Something's not right here.
你看到了吗？
You seeing this?
我看到了
Yeah, I see it.
看来我们晚了一步
So we're in the wrong place.
上车，我们走
HUNTER: Let's go! Let's go!
安啦！只有车子受伤而已
Relax, I only killed the car.
又是你
You again!
在宫殿里，发生什么事？
Back at the palace, what happened in there?
他在那里，等你的信息
He was there, waiting for a message from you.
而我就是信差
I was the messenger.
然后呢？
And?
还能怎样！
What do you think?
他儿子根本不在乎，他不想回沙漠
His boy in there didn't give a shit.
所以不会有什么石油工程动工
He's not going back to the desert, so there'll be no oil contracts.
一切全都是徒劳无功
It was all for nothing.
原来如此！
Is that right?
这是赢家礼物…
And the winner is.
这就是你们要的？
So that's what this is all about.
对，精彩的现在才要开始
Yeah, it's all hookers and blow from here on in.
你就是不懂，对吧？
You just don't get it, do you?
别拿它！
Ditch it.
你确定？
You sure?
全丢掉
Ditch it.
这是俘虏的补偿
I gotta cover my expenses.
你不能回英国
You can't go back to England.
杀了那特务后更不行
Not after killing that spook.
你到底是谁？
Who the fuck are you?
我是您老师！经验之谈
Who, me? The voice of experience.
你打算要去哪？
Where are you going to go?
你打算做什么？
What are you going to do?
你会需要这个
You're going to need this.
新名字、新脸孔、新的人生
New name, new face, new papers.
很贵的，你等着瞧吧
Expensive. You'll see.
真浪费！
Damn shame.
你们以为可以就这么走人？
You think you get to just walk away?
没人能走
Nobody walks away.
我、你 都逃不了
Not me or you, none of us.
你刚杀死的老家伙
The old man you just killed,
他说除非双边同意
he told me a war isn't over
战争才会结束
until both sides say it is.
但对我而言还没结束
Well, I'm telling you now, this is over for me.
你要我说什么？祝你幸福吗？
Really? And what? You want me to say, "Me, too," and then it's happy ever after?
随你便！
Your choice.
他们宣称这场战争已结束
You know, when I got this, they told me my war was over.
都是在鬼扯，你自己小心！
I told them they were full of shit. Now I'm telling it to you.
快滚吧！
Let it go.
你要去哪里？
So where are you going?
怎么？想来作客？
What, are you planning a visit?
这很难说
You never know.
你要是来，我会招待你
You come. I'll be waiting.
我们会在机场帮你叫车
We'll call you a cab from the airport.
你是安吗？穿怪怪雨鞋的那个？
Aren't you Anne Frazer? The girl with those weird gumboots?
你是丹尼，落跑的那个？
Are you Danny Bryce, the boy who went away?
对，我回来了
Yeah. I'm back.
你要去哪？
Where you headed?
漫无目的…
I don't know.
我也是，要一起走吗？
Me, neither. Want to come along?
电影改编自 菲恩斯博士
“羽毛人The Feather Man”
真实故事，口述撰写
出版当时
引起诸多争议与政府不满
当时参与阿曼战争的英国航特部队
是掠夺资源还是正义申张
至今仍对此任务保持高度机密
丹尼和史派基探员
目前行踪仍然不明。